the Prudential Uganda chief executive
director Tate aitevi who launched the
project at coma Secondary School said
their plan is to have a project that
serves over 15 000 school going children
who have been struggling to access Safe
Drinking Water the process affecting
their time of learning and exposing them
to water-borne diseases according to the
Prudential CEO the project will be
delivered in a period of one month first
schools would have to spend money to buy
a firewood spend money to build this
water by chlorine tablets and the impact
of that is negative in two ways we need
to cut down trees to be able to get this
firewood and that's impacting the
environment negatively but it's also the
financial stress on schools having to
make the money available to do this
the program itself should end up
probably covering close to 15 000
children who completed in a month
and this is just the beginning for us
where we see opportunity to do more good
we will come back to in Bali and expand
it a little more further he said that
the lack of Clean safe drinking water in
schools has resulted into illness the
high school dropouts among others noting
that 70 of the diseases afflicting
school going children are waterborne
the issue of safe drinking water is a
right for every child of school going
age the impact of not having safe
drinking water means that school
dropouts are increased teachers struggle
to get students on course because if you
are out in and out of class because of
sickness it's difficult to make sure the
curriculum that Madame and team have put
together and implementing is properly
taught out it's difficult if people are
in and out of the classroom so there's
an impact on the quality of Education
that students will receive
and we looked around and we thought that
this was a good idea for us to invest in
but a couple of numbers that caught my
attention
that for all the sicknesses reported for
children of school going age
70 percent of these diseases were water
related issues with the water safety the
embalanced city education officer Linus
nashimu commanded Prudential for the
initiative noting that they have had a
challenge of accessing clean drinking
water in schools in the city she asked
Prudential to extend the project to
several other schools within mbala City
to help to assure that Learners have
easy access to Safe clean drinking water
so credential Uganda support has not
only provided Lifeline to our schools by
chance also creating a pathway to
uninterrupted education for our students
just like it has been measured their
children get clean water
safer and clean water they have good
toilet facilities
I don't see a reason why that girl child
will be upset because it's lacking there
is no washroom there is not really the
water to change there's no things like
that so I want to appreciate you so much
The Uncommon Secondary School Deputy
teacher Kevin amusukult said that the
school has been struggling to provide
safe drinking water to over 6 000
students she noted that the project will
go a long way in proving a sustainable
solution to the challenge posed by the
high bills the school pays to National
Water and Sewage Corporation because of
the school because of the big population
we have cannot
managed to take control or to supply the
water fully in school
and you're coming today to give us the
package you're giving us today we are so
grateful we have been thinking about her
about it I say God has answered our
prayer by your coming we appreciate so
much the CEO you don't know how we are
so happy
that you came and you chose us this time
around
conveniently uh play the foundation okay
so we have